Fellas, we got the game plan crew back
together again. Welcome in our head
coach, Dan Quinn, who has been very,
very busy, man. Getting your guy in
round one. We saw your excitement when
we drafted Sunny Styles, man. You even
had a little curse word to say to the
camera. That was so fly. But he was also
excited to be here. He said
>> this morning, I told my parents, I'mma
be a commander. I don't care what nobody
else says, man. How happy are you to
have a guy like that in the building?
>> It was awesome. And uh it speaks to
maybe the environment that collectively
everybody's creating here
>> and it's one about like absolutely
putting it all in to be your best and
that's at every part not just coaches
and players but everybody pouring into
one another to see how far we can take
it and you have good standards like that
and people want to be a part of it um I
think there's no telling where it can
go.
>> So coach I mean obviously you were
excited I was excited. BC was excited.
It was it was exciting time. The thing
that got me was like I thought there was
no way he was going to get there at
seven. Obviously Tennessee drafts the
receiver. When did you start to kind of
say maybe our guy is going to be there
at seven?
>> It was after the fourth round pick.
>> And so then you go right into what's the
first rule of Fight Club? You don't talk
about
>> Don't talk about Fight Club.
>> And so okay, there's a chance here that
this could go down. And uh so then
they're waiting. Trade comes in with
Kansas City. just again fight club
rules, right?
>> And uh so then you know once that
happened uh you know Adam was right
there already had the number on the
postit and uh cleared way for the phone
call to take place and so
>> um it was such a uh clear representative
like you put so much in the ball what he
can bring to our team and uh yeah really
pumped to have him here
>> and coach a little earlier you said what
we're building here and that is what
Sunny Styles talked about. I got to
interview him right after he was drafted
and he said the people in the building
he said that's what made me buy in Ohio
State that's what made me buy into here.
How happy does that make you that the
culture you've built in such a short
time is permeating like that where all
these players free agents as well come
in and say this is the place I want to
be. Yeah, 26 feels like um a new start
in some ways and sometimes you don't
need a new place to have a new start.
And so the 25 season was so difficult
for a lot of us. And so to have some of
the free agents, you feel their energy
coming in, having, you know, draft picks
like Sunny coming, being a part of it.
There is a freshness that goes with
that. Uh we're excited that he's here.
We're excited what he's where he's
going. And like we're also excited like
to be on this journey with him,
>> you know, to see where he can get to
because I really think it's going to be
a bar that's super high and uh that's
something that you want to strive for as
a coach to say, can we take him to that
place?
>> You talked about something I think is
interesting is like where he's going.
You know, when AP was in here yesterday,
he talked about like from the first game
to the last game of last season, you saw
a dramatic improvement. When you cut on
the tape of him at Ohio State, like what
do you see from him? I think the speed
and the violence of action, those are
the things that jump out to me because
>> just gave me chills right there.
>> Speed and violence. Love that.
>> Like there's a specific play um you know
watching it just Saturday night. I was
just reviewing and I can remember
watching my iPad. I was sitting next to
Stace and I was like damn. And she's
like what? I showed her the play. It was
against Illinois and it was a four- yard
game but he was a curl player going to
and the the explosion on the running
back to knock him out of bounds was just
remarkable. So the four-yard gain of
that, it wouldn't have shown up anywhere
on the stat sheet, but the speed, the
finish, the balance that it was there,
it's a
over and over again, can you train
somebody into that space because not
everybody has that in their body to be
able to do it. And so you combine that
with the work ethic, the humility, how
much he loves the game, like you put all
that together, you really get fired up
about what it could be.
>> Yeah. And I think when you talk about
what it could be, I see a guy at Ohio
State who's in multiple spots. like he's
kind of playing like a pseudo nickel
position. He's on the ball, he's off the
ball. How important is that flexibility
for you and in the Serant Jones defense?
>> Yeah. Anytime you you played another
position a good bit of your career, like
so he was a defensive back. Yeah.
>> You know, coming up through high school
and two years at college where he played
safety. So being in that room and the
communication, the techniques that go
involved with it, now you get to apply
those skills to a different position,
you're already elevated at those skills.
covering man-to-man, knowing zones, how
to play that.
>> That's a unique thing that you're able
to do and bring. And so, the best
linebackers have the
>> for sure the speed and the athletic
ability to play safety. And so, I'm glad
that he got two years to develop and
hone those skills because it happens so
much quicker. The line of scrimmage, the
blocks that get to you differently. And
so, you to really improve you have to
have self-awareness. And I asked him in
specific, what did you want to see
better from 24 and a 25? And it was like
clearly demonstrated.
>> That's cool.
>> And all those things you mentioned,
you're hearing that versatility. That's
what Dvonte Jones came in here and said
he wanted. He wanted players like that.
So I have to ask that reaction from
Donte Jones. We know you were excited.
What did Donte Jones say when y'all got
this guy?
>> Low key. He you know he gets excited,
but he's not. He's like smiling and you
can see that brain already working. He
gave a just a fantastic overview um on
the first day with the veterans here
this week about the defense and what it
could look like. I think it's important
for all ball players to zoom out. All
right, what's the identity? How are we
going to play and then zoom back into
the specific skills. And so what I like
about this is he's adding into a strong
group the speed that we've added through
the off season from at linebacker with
Leo and Odaf and Casey and now you're
adding Sunny as well and Frankie and
Jordan and the speed that I'm hoping to
see from our defense. I think there'll
be a remarkable difference.
>> And it seems like you got kind of a fun
unique challenge with that, you know,
middle level of the defense. You got
three dudes who are really unique
athletes. Like they can rush, they can
cover, they're physically violent like
you were talking about. Like how do you
make sure that all kind of works and
like you know what is your hand in that
kind of
>> I've been through that some other times
before and the best way to teach some of
it is just by concept. So you may have
the safety position, but this is the
technique or this linebacker. And so
safety's at linebacker, linebacker's at
safety ends who can play down on the
line. So when you teach the concept, it
doesn't matter what we letter the
person. It's can you do this skill? It's
kind of like in basketball, can a big
guy, you know, bring the ball up? Yeah,
if he can. You don't have to just, you
know, give it to somebody else. So, it's
those types of things that allow
identifications to be difficult for an
offense. Knowing like why is this person
over here and not to the where he's
supposed to be and then blitz them or
play him from off and there's a
disguise. And if you can put mental and
physical pressure on the offense, that's
really what you're looking to do. And we
definitely have the speed to now put the
physical. So, the scheme has got to put
the mental pressure on. That's how you
can really affect an offense. And it's
cool to hear you talk about that because
that's something that's becoming more in
vogue, right? Is like this you're
teaching concept. Yes. Is that something
Donte is bringing with him here? Because
that's that's really exciting, I think.
>> Yeah, I think it's important. Think of
all the offenses that can check things
at the line of scrimmage and offenses
have been ahead of defenses for a few
years in that way of finding the best
look, finding what they want to run. And
so now defenses are starting to catch
up, putting people in different
locations, having their own checks and
balances at the line of scrimmage. So
the offense doesn't get into a premier
play against a look they want. And so
the defenses are now
>> checking that as well. And so you have
to have versatile players, Logan, to do
that because what you may your
responsibility at the start of the play
may be different when you check it.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> And think of a run to a pass on offense.
well, could be simple as like a blitz to
a coverage on defense. And so having the
ability to have versatility certainly
allows you to do that.
>> And coach, you've talked about wanting
to bring guys in here that are
commanders, that have a certain type of
pedigree, a certain type of morality, if
you will. And we know a guy in Sunny
Styles. He's only 21. Yes.
>> But he shows that leadership quality. He
wore the number zero Ohio State. We know
what that means. Talk to me about the
person that is Sunny Styles and made you
say he's the perfect fit for Washington.
Yeah, he's definitely has a um some
traits of football, the preparation, the
um like the game, the like what he takes
care of his body, the training that the
great players have. And so we won't
compare him to, you know, great players
because it's important for him to go on
his own journey. I don't want him to be
somebody else, but he has the traits of
the great players that want to do the
unrequired work, want to find it out,
figure it out. And so, um, you know,
like a guy like London, you know, who
just finds any edge they can to say,
"All right,
>> this can happen." He has those type of
traits about him. And those are the
things that allow you to ascend really
fast because like you're not going to
take any other way than to figure it
out. And so like he's figured a lot out.
>> Yeah. And you you talked about how
special he is, you know, like as a
person. And I don't want to put any like
expectations on him, but have you ever
had a rookie signal caller for a defense
in your career?
>> Um we did it once in Atlanta with a
linebacker named Dion Jones.
>> Dude, Dion Devbo. Legend. Yeah.
>> And uh so he was, you know, quick
linebacker coming out and that was good.
And the nice part about now Logan is
because of the colleges are now doing
that as well. Oh, with a with a radio.
That's right.
>> That helps because it's not as big a
transition to go and do that, but um it
does help that you can get into that
spot to do that. And so if they're
ready, um it's worth it
>> to get that development. We did it with
Wags. I wasn't there as rookie year, but
Ken was and so he would be another
linebacker that from the very beginning
as a rookie. Um, let it, called it, and
they became an excellent unit, you know,
with Wags right in the middle of the
communication hub of everything in
Seattle. But when he got there, he did
it right away.
>> Coach, we appreciate your time. We know
you're a busy, man, so we're going to
let you get going cuz it's still
>> tonight. Are you ready? You guys already
I'm about to say I was about to ask you
if you was going to give us a little bit
of inside information.
>> Hell no.
>> That's not how we do it here in Command
Atlanta. We appreciate you, coach. Game
plan crew back together again, coach.
Good luck tonight.
>> Yeah, good to see you guys.
>> Thank you, sir.